Let's discuss Android of athletes overlays, or RRO, are one of the most essential techniques for customizing
Android.
I you.
So what exactly is an overlay or ARRL?
In simple words, a runtime resource overlay, or RRO, is a package that changes the resource values
of a target package.
So for now, just imagine it as an epic game with only resource files in it.
So what can be overlaid by using the RRO technique?
So Ororo can technically overlay all the resource files like layouts, screens, colors and other similar
sorts files.
It can also overlay drivers and fonts.
So by doing this, you could dynamically change the look and feel of an application or a system UI component.
So in this simple example, you could see that a blue android is changed into a green android by using
the resource overlays.
It could be either runtime or static overlays what cannot be overlaid by arrows.
So you cannot overlay any source code.
That means the Java or Kotlin source code files and would be overlaid.
So, for example, if you consider the application structure, you can overlay water coming under the
resource field and water coming under the SIRC folder, which is the Java and codling classes that cannot
be overlooked.
So let's have a closer look at the RRO overlay process.
So this diagram shows a high level overview of how an application is compiled, executed and overlaid
by an arrow.
So that top section shows how a normal Android application is converted into an Android epic and executed.
And the bottom part shows how an RRO project gets converted into an RRO, a beacon and gets overlaid
into the process.
So in case of a normal Android application, we have mainly these files, right?
So the Android Manifest Dot example is one of the code files where we configure a lot of things for
that application.
And then we have the Java and Kotlin files where we like the business logic and other logic.
Right?
And also, we have the resources folder where we have all the UI elements like the layout and other
images or drawing ability to use product or the resource folder is the one which we are actually overlaying,
right?
So when this project is built, it gets converted into an epic.
And if you open up any beginning, you can see that within that there is the Android Manifest or text
someone.
And then we have got the closest known text file, which is basically the compiled form of Java and
Kotlin files.
And then we have got the resources, not add a C file, which is basically a compiled form of the resource
facts.
So during the execution, the AI process will make use of the classes or index and Apatosaurus Resources,
not ADC, to run the application.
So that's how a normal Android application runs.
So when there is a RRO in scope, then we how RRO the source of stored ADC and RRO ID map as well within
the process?
OK.
So RRO resources stored at a C is nothing but the overlay.
Enable Resources, which is available within the RRO epic and the RRO IED map, is nothing but a tamper
which has a one or one mapping the available resources.
OK, so now let's have a look at the RRO section.
So in normal, RRO Project will consist of only an Android manifest or example and the resource files.
So on completion or own build process, this will get converted into an RRO API game and in the RRO
epic game, that'll be the Android Manifest cortex similar and the resources don't add a C file.
So the resources store to add a C file is nothing but a compiler form of resources file during the execution
process.
The AI process will pick up this particular resources also stored at a C, and it will look at the RRO
IED map to get the corresponding resource IED for the overlay the source.
And during the runtime, it will basically overlay the App Resources Store DRC with the RRO Resource
Note and a C, so please note that only the particular resource will get overlaid.
So for example, if you are only overlaying a layout example, then only that particular example will
get all.
The rest of the resources will be used from Apple stores and start at a scene.
So in short, during the runtime, the AI process will look at the RRO ID map and gets the right all
the label to society and overlay that resource on top of the app.
The source code at us.
So that's how an RRO overlay process worked on it very high level.
So let's consider a real world application of static and dynamic RRO.
Consider an example of mobile manufacturers like Samsung, Motorola or Nokia, so they could use a static
overlay or creating different brands of mobile phones.
So in this case, you can see Brand X and Brand Y are created from a single AOSP system image.
So similarly, they could use dynamic arrows to create different skins for a system.
OK.
So as you could see here, on top of Brand X and Y, they could use dynamic arrows and create a blue
skin and a nice skin.
So here is the difference between static and dynamic arrows.
The static arrows are applied at the build time and cannot be deactivated or disabled later, whereas
dynamic arrow arrows are enabled at runtime and it can be programmatically enabled or disabled at a
later stage.
Thank you.